PROFILE

5+ years experienced principal software programmer at Marsh McLennan | Full Stack | Node.js, Express, Nestjs, Angular, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, Azure, AWS, DevOps, TypeORM, Docker, Kubernetes, Github Workflows, Rancher, JFrog Artifactory | CDAC certified | BE in Computer science.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal Software Engineer, *Marsh McLennan* ☑

May 2022 - present | Powai, Mumbai, India

Working on a leading Romanian and Bulgarian insurance portal from car makers, insurers to customers.

Involved MMGS Global movement to OSS2.0

<u>Tech Stack</u>: **Angular, Nodejs, Postgres, Docker, Kubernetes, Github Workflows, Rancher, JFrog Artifactory**.

Software Pragrammer, *JiBe ERP* □

Sep 2018 - May 2022 | Navi Mumbai, India

- Involved in full product life cycle from design and development to deployment from scratch.
- Developed core features of the Web based ERP like User access right system, Vessel machinery assignment, voyage estimate, PMS, etc.
- Mentored a team of 4 and 6 members, overseeing development work efforts and quality.
- Worked on multiple projects simultaneously.
- Server-Side development includes:
 - Module's ER Diagrams Using DB Schema
 - API development using Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server, MongoDB.
 - Generic utility node modules and JavaScript libraries.
 - Created API authentication, Audit Trail, Logging Middleware in utility node modules.
 - Developed backend scheduler for multi server data synchronisation.
 - Code Deployment using Azure Pipelines.
 - PM2 setup for load balancing and process management.
 - DB Migration using **TypeORM** from **SQL server** to **MongoDB**.
- Client-side development includes: Consuming APIs,
- Generic component creation in **Angular** using primeng.
- Troubleshooting, Debugging issues and bugs.
- Impact Analysis, Code review and maintaining best practices.

EDUCATION

CDAC, PG Diploma in advanced computing

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018 | Mumbai, India | First Class

University of Mumbai, BE Computer Science

May 2013 – May 2017 | Mumbai, India | First Class

Prabhash Gupta

Principal Software Engineer

- Powai, 400076 Mumbai, India
- (C) +919028607880
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/prabhashgupta/
- https://github.com/prabhashgupta
- https://leetcode.com/prabhash0995/
- <u>| ≥</u> Stackover<u>flow</u>

SKILLS

Programming languages

JavaScript, Typescript, C#, Handlebars, Java

Nodejs

crypto, zlib, axios, mongodb, mssql, typeorm, nestjs, jest, handlebars, puppeteer, amqplib, jsreport, surveyjs, many more..

Frameworks & Libraries

Express, TypeORM, Nestjs, Angular, Electron, PrimeNG, Socket.io

Message Queue

RabbitMQ

Process Manager

PM2

Database

SQL Server, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Source Control

GIT

Cloud

Microsoft Azure, AWS

Tools

Rancher, Datadog, JFrog, HashiCorp Vault, DB Schema, Draw.io

Operating System

Linux, Windows

PROJECTS

PMS, Planned maintenance system

Sep 2021 - present

- Impact analysis for integrating new features to the existing system.
- Created technical design and dev estimation.
- Assisting three sub teams in development efforts.
- Code review, bug resolving and implementing complex logic.

VMA, Vessel Machinery Assignment

Jul 2021 - Jan 2022

- Implemented a message queue system using RabbotMQ for 2.5 million records on one click with zero tolerance for data loss.
- Created flowchart with draw.io for entire process.
- Created a separate node microservice using amqplib.

Voyage Estimate

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021

- This module provides average daily revenue performance of a vessel which facilitates charterers in making commercial decision.
- Responsible for entire backend development.

Port call weather forecast

Sep 2020 - Oct 2020

JCDS, JiBe's centralized database system

Mar 2020 - Aug 2020

This module is the first module in JiBe which connected all the JiBe's client servers to single centralized server also it is the first module to introduce MongoDB in the JiBe's ecosystem.

Responsible to create API code structure from scratch using MongoDB native node module.

Voyage Manager

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020

- Provides vessels port summary, port activity and cargo details for a single journey.
- Responsible for entire backend development.

Vessel Schedule

Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

- Provides detailed information about the movement of a vessel from one port to another.
- Responsible for entire backend development.

J3 Infra, *JiBe's Version 3 Infrastructure for office and vessel* Added API - Login, Logger, Admin Libraries, Upload/Download, OData, System Level Filter, DB Migration, Audit Trail

TECH STACK USED

PMS - Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server, RabbitMQ

PMS - Frontend

Angular 9, PrimeNG, Syncfusion

VMA - Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server, RabbitMQ, AWS, amqplib

VMA - Frontend

Angular 9, PrimeNG, Syncfusion

Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server, MongoDB

Frontend

Angular 9

Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server, MongoDB

Backend

Nodejs, Express, MongoDB, SQL Server, RabbitMQ, AWS, amqplib

Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL server

Frontend

Angular 8

Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server

Frontend

Angular 8

Backend

Nodejs, TypeORM, Express, SQL Server, odata-v4-mssql, busboy